<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on data science</title>
    <link>/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on data science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 16:59:13 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analytics Lifecycle</title>
      <link>/blog/data-analytics-lifecyle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 16:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/data-analytics-lifecyle/</guid>
      <description>Data analytics takes a lot of time. You have to clean the dataset, figure out what&amp;rsquo;s what and start thinking about which variables are going to help you answer your question. This should lead to some data exploration. You need to get a feel of what you are working with so that you can decide how to approach your question with what you have (or you find what your missing and try to aggregate it).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crime in Chicago</title>
      <link>/projects/crime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 16:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/crime/</guid>
      <description>For my project, I will be looking at crime in Chicago, Illinois in 2018. The primary focus of this project is to try to predict if an arrest will happen as a result of the crime. The data is coming from the Chicago police department and was downloaded from this website. Originally the data set has crime information from 2001 to 2019, but I want to focus on the most recent full year, 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCMC Methods</title>
      <link>/projects/mcmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 16:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/mcmc/</guid>
      <description>Markov chain Monte Carlo methods are used to estimate the posterior distribution of a parameter of interest. We draw samples from the estimated posterior distribution in order to compute statistics from that distribution. The two main methods I have been looking at are the Metropolis-Hastings algorithm and the other is using Hamiltonian Dynamics.
The interactive web app&amp;rsquo;s purpose is to help understand the difference between the two methods. There is an introduction to Bayesian statistics, each method, and then three examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethics and Data Science in Society</title>
      <link>/blog/ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 16:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ethics/</guid>
      <description>Cathy O’Neil discusses the problems and ethics with using data science in her book Weapons of Math Destruction. In one chapter she discusses the U.S. News college ranking, it’s development, and it’s consequences. It was the choice of what was deemed important for a college to have in order for the student to succeed that I see as the problem. A problem with this is that people were trying to cheat the system and raise their score without really deserving it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critique of an /r/dataisbeautiful Post</title>
      <link>/blog/critique/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 15:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/critique/</guid>
      <description>I was looking through the /r/dataisbeautiful thread and the one that stood out the most was one where they posted a link to their website, Flickmatrix where combine Rotten Tomato, IDMb, Letterboxd, and Metacritic scores with what’s available on Netflix and Amazon Video.
I looked throughout the site to find a blurb about where the data was being collected from but I could not find anything. So, I went back to the thread and looked for a comment or such, and all that was explained was that they got the information from their respective website, but was not responding to the comments that were asking about how they were getting information from Netflix, which makes me think they might have been sneaking around.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>